Now, in most cases,
ところで 多くの場合
the behavior layer might not send
行動レイヤーは到達するための正確な終了構成ではなく
an exact end configuration to reach but rather an approximate one like that.
おおよそのものを送信するかもしれません
Therefore, we want to identify a varied goal state that leads our vehicle in
そのため この他方の車線に送信されているおおよその終了構成に
the approximate end configuration that's being sent to us here in the other lane.
車両を導く 有効な目標状態を特定する必要があります
Now, that's where our sampling based approach comes in handy.
これが サンプリングベースのアプローチが役立つところです
We don't know for sure what a good end state is.
良い終了状態がどのようなものであるかは明確にわかりません
Even if we receive an exact S&amp;amp;D co-ordinate from the behavior layer,
行動レイヤーから正確な s と d の座標を受け取ったとしても
we still have to find a good end velocity and acceleration for our car.
車にとって良い終了速度と加速を見つける必要があります
Most times, S&amp;amp;D aren't fixed either.
多くの場合 s と d はどちらも固定ではありません
Therefore, we want to sample a large number of end configurations
したがって 膨大な数の終了構成が 車を運転したいおおよその
are on the approximate desired position that we wish to drive our car to.
目的の位置にあることをサンプリングしたいのです
And we generate the corresponding Jerk minimizing
そして 各ゴール構成に対応した
trajectories for each goal configuration.
躍度最小トラジェクトリーを生成します
Then, we discard all non-derivable trajectories,
その後 予測レイヤーによって予測された
all trajectories that collide with the road boundaries,
導き出せないすべてのトラジェクトリー つまり道路境界 他の車両
or with other vehicles or pedestrians as predicted by the prediction layer.
または歩行者にぶつかるすべてのトラジェクトリーを排除します
Now, we have a nice set of derivable trajectories which are all collision free and
これで 導き出せるトラジェクトリーの優れたセットができました 衝突がなく スタートおよび
Jerk optimal in each dimension with respect to the start and goal configurations.
ゴール構成に対する各次元においての最適な躍度になっているものです
We need to decide which one the car should follow.
車がどれに従うべきか決定する必要があります
That means we need to rank them,
つまりランク付けが必要です
which we are going to do by defining a cost function.
これはコスト関数を定義して行います
What makes sense as a cost function?
コスト関数として何がわかりますか?
First, consider Jerk.
まず 躍度を考えます
For each pair of end configurations,
終了構成の各ペアに対して
a quintic polynomial is Jerk optimal.
5 次多項式が躍度的に最適です
But given that all the trajectories obtained are different final configuration,
でも 取得されたすべてのトラジェクトリーが異なる最終構成だとすると
maybe some are better than others.
他よりも良いものがいくつかあるかもしれません
In addition to that,
それに加えて
we want to consider longitudinal versus lateral Jerk.
縦方向と横方向の躍度について考えなければなりません
What is worse for comfort?
快適性ついて よくないものは何ですか?
Turns out that side to side Jerk is more uncomfortable.
横方向の躍度が最も不快であることがわかります
So we want to prioritize minimizing that over minimizing longitudinal Jerk.
ですから 縦方向の躍度の最小化よりも 横方向の躍度の最小化を優先したいのです
Next, consider distance to obstacles.
次に障害物への距離を考えます
Given these two configurations,
これらの 2 つの構成を考えると
we would prefer being further away from
他方の車両のリアバンパーのすぐ近くにある状況よりも
the other vehicle to a situation where we are right next to their rear bumper.
車両からだいぶ離れているほうが良いでしょう
Also, we want to consider distance to center line.
さらに 中央線への距離も考えます
We might prefer to be close to the center of the line.
きっと車線の中央に近い方がいいと思うでしょう
So, in choosing between these two scenarios,
そのため これら 2 つのシナリオから選ぶ場合は
maybe we would prefer the one on the right.
右側のものが良いと思うかもしれません
Finally, it is time to go.
最後に ゴールまでの時間です
All else being equal given the final S,
他がすべて同じで 最終の S が与えられていれば
we would prefer to arrive at our destination earlier rather than later.
遅いよりかは早く目的地に着きたいでしょう
So we might prefer this situation.
ですからこの状況がよいと思うでしょう
And there are plenty of other cost functions one might think of.
そして それ以外のたくさんのコスト関数が思い浮かぶでしょう
The tricky part is balancing all of these costs correctly.
複雑なのは これらのコストすべてについて正確にバランスをとることです
Often, our goals conflict.
よく 目標が対立することがあります
So the trajectory that minimizes
横方向の躍度を最小化するトラジェクトリーが
lateral Jerk may not be the one that keeps us closest to the center line.
中央線の最も近くを維持するものではないかもしれません
In practice, most of the hard work is in the details of balancing these cost functions.
実際 困難な作業のほとんどが これらのコスト関数のバランスの詳細です
Now that we have defined all these cost functions
これらコスト関数をすべて定義し
and combined them into one weighted cost function,
これらを 1 つの重み付きのコスト関数に統合したので
we can look back at the scenario we just saw and use
さきほど見たシナリオに戻り
the supplied cost functions to calculate the cost for each trajectory.
準備したコスト関数を使用して各トラジェクトリーのコストを計算します
For example, this trajectory looks nice.
たとえば このトラジェクトリーは良いように見えます
However, its rather close to the boundary of the lane.
でも 車線の境界にかなり近いです
And even more important,
もっと重要なのは
it is close to another moving vehicle.
別の移動中の車両に近いことです
Remember that we have to consider
障害物への距離を見たときに
the full car dimension when looking at distance to obstacles.
車全体の寸法を考えなければなりません
And in this case, we would be dangerously close to another car.
この場合 もうひとつの車に危険なほど近いことになります
Therefore, we would associate a high cost with this trajectory.
したがって このトラジェクトリーには高いコストを関連付けることになります
Similarly, we don't like these two trajectories too
同様に この 2 つのトラジェクトリーもあまり気に入りません
much because they make us drive on this side of the lane.
というのは車線のこちら側を運転させるからです
And there is not really a reason for that in this scenario.
それに このシナリオでそうすることの理由が本当にありません
So, they would be associated with a high cost as well.
ですからこれらも高いコストに関連付けられるでしょう
Regarding these two trajectories,
この 2 つのトラジェクトリーについて
they're okay but the lateral Jerk associated with them would be
これらは OK ですが これらに関連付けられた横方向の躍度は
higher than for trajectories whose end configuration has a larger S value.
終了構成に大きい S 値があるトラジェクトリーのものより高くなるでしょう
Therefore, they would be associated with a medium cost.
そのため これらは中間のコストに関連付けられます
Now, consider the last trajectory.
では 最後のトラジェクトリーを考えましょう
It's nice and smooth,
良い感じでスムースです
it doesn't turn too fast,
急激に向きを変えていません
we end up moving further away along the road,
道路に沿って遠くまで移動します
none of our cost functions end up with a higher value.
コスト関数で高い値で終わっているものはありません
Therefore, when we combine them,
したがって これらを統合すると
this trajectory gets a low cost and ends up being selected.
このトラジェクトリーのコストが低くなり 選択されることになります